http://www.espen.org/espen/privacy-policy

Last Updated: 24 May 2018
Privacy Policy
The European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) comes into force on May 25th 2018 and has major implications worldwide. European citizens now have multiple digital rights over their personal details, including the right to be asked to provide consent for the storage of personal details in a database, the right to be asked to provide consent to be contacted, the right to see the personal information stored, the right to be forgotten including having all personal details permanently removed from a database, the right to know who this information is shared with (consent is also required for this), and the right to be contacted should a significant data breach occur. All of these changes must be prospectively acknowledged by the user and cannot be presumed to have occurred. The proof rests with the websites to be able to demonstrate consent has been obtained. It is likely almost all websites in the world will move to this model, unless they wish to limit access to European citizens, which would be difficult technically. Fines for non-compliance with this can reach €20 million. As a result, we have updated our privacy policy accordingly. We took as example the updated privacy policy of The International Fluid Academy https://www.fluidacademy.org which is a solid example.
What information do we collect about you?
When registering with the ESPEN as a member, individually or by your national society, we collect some basic information about you. This is required to send the newsletter and inform us about the clinicians using this site so we can best tailor our services to your requirements. Some information is also needed for us to ensure your membership advantages (reduced rates for registration to ESPEN events and LLL live modules, subscription to the ESPEN journals, access to archived educational Congress presentations, access to Research Fellowship grants, access to Travel Fellowship for communication at the ESPEN congress etc.).
When you register with ESPEN to the free subscription plan for the Live Long Learning Program for Clinical Nutrition and Metabolism we collect some basic information about you. This is required to provide a full spectrum of services to our students of the LLL program. We collect information about your performance on online quizzes and about your results from LLL live courses.
How do we collect this information?
Your details are collected using the website & newsletter registration page, either through information you completed yourself or through information collected and provided to us by your national society.
How will we use the information about you?
Your information is used to send the ESPEN newsletter and to inform you about the changing contents of the website and meetings. It is also used to fulfill our engagements towards your membership advantages (see hereunder – who is your information shared with).
Who is your information shared with?
The newsletters are sent via ACYMAILING, a standard commercial emailing facility, who have access to your email address for this purpose only. They DO NOT receive your personal contact details.
Basic information (your name and full postal address) is also communicated to Elsevier for activation of your subscription to Clinical Nutrition journal hard copies as part of your membership advantages. It is also shared with MCI for membership check upon your registration to the annual congress (preferential rates for ESPEN members).
At last, basic information (your name and full postal address) needs also to be provided each year to the RCS “Registre de Commerce et des Sociétés” (Commercial and Societies Registry) in Luxembourg as part of legal obligations of ESPEN as a NPO based in Grand Duchy of Luxembourg (Art. 10 of the modified Law of the 21st of April 1928 on associations and non- profit foundations). The list has to indicate, in alphabetical order, the names, first names, address and nationality of the NPO members. The member list is recorded in RCS files but not published.
Marketing
We do not share your details with any 3rd parties. Any future relationship will be to enable ESPEN to add or replace functionality. We do not share or sell your details with commercial parties for the purpose of them contacting you independently of ESPEN.
Access to your information and correction
You have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. This is available via your profile page, accessible through the login facility. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please download them via your profile page, accessible via the login facility, or email us (membership@espen.org) If your details are incorrect, or you would like to update them, you can do so via your profile page.
Right to be Forgotten
If you wish for your details to be removed from our database please contact us: membership@espen.org and lllhelpdesk@espen.org
By asking to be fully removed from our database, you agree implicitly that you may not pursue your Membership with us.
Cookies
Cookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behavior information. This information can be used to track visitor use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity. For further information visit  www.aboutcookies.org or  www.allaboutcookies.org.
On the website www.espen.org we do use cookies with our Content Management System, which is Joomla. Joomla uses cookies to store information about a number of things. These include your session, which means it saves information on what you have done on the site during this current visit (for example what pages you have visited and whether you have logged in). We also use google analytics to generate viewing statistics for the site, which are not identifiable to any individual. This data is used to enhance your experience when you visit the website: we make items often looked for easier to access.
Other Websites
ESPEN.org and lllnutrition.com contain links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to this website so when you link to other websites you should read their privacy policies.
Changes to our privacy policy
We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on May 22th 2018, to align with the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
How to contact us
Please email us  if you have any questions about our privacy policy or information we hold about you.
Share
Tweet
Main Menu
About UsCommitteesExecutive CommitteeScientific CommitteeEducational and Clinical Practice CommitteeECP Committee associatedCouncil Country RepresentativeMedical Nutrition Int. Industry (MNI)Past ESPEN OfficersHonorsHonorary MembersCareer Achievement AwardCuthbertson Lecture AwardWretlind Lecture AwardAimsHistoryConstitutionOrganization ChartJournalsespenwaytohealthMalnutrition - Another Weight ProblemTwitter feedPrivacy PolicyLogin FormContact UsCongress2020 ESPEN CongressOrganise a CongressSessions on-line accessPast CongressMembersJoin ESPENFAQSubscribeMy DashboardMember AccountMembershipsEducationTrainingInformation on TrainingESPEN Training Centres in Clinical NutritionEducational GrantElectronic Video LibraryPearls of Knowledge 2018Pearls of Knowledge 2015Pearls of Knowledge 2013Public ESPEN Videos / MediaLLL ProgrammeESPEN CoursesESPEN Blue BookSpecial InterestSpecial Interest GroupsDietitiansPharmacistsnutritionDay in EuropeScientific ActivitiesSocietiesNational Societies part of ESPEN CouncilNational Societies PresidentsGuidelinesESPEN GuidelinesGuideline AppGuideline Web-versionGuidelines in ProgressGuideline ServicesGuideline Work ForumLLLJoin LLL for FREEGo to LLLnutrition.com
